3/21/2017 ResumeHelp

OSORO OKARI MICHAEL

175 KISII-40200, NAIROBI, KE 40200

MOBILE: +254 711560619 | osoromichael@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a competent, self-motivated, innovation oriented and result oriented person in my endeavors. I am able to work under pressure with minimal supervision and deliver within deadlines. To engage in career activities that will allow for progress in term of skills, expertise, social economic development and innovation through exposure to new ideas for personal, professional and growth of the field of interest.

SKILLS

- Microsoft office packages.
- Web programming.
- PHP -CodeIgniter
- Python(flask) -Beginner
- Javascript
 - Ajax
 - Angularjs
 - JQuery
- Google Maps Integration
- · API Development
- · Version Control git

- HTML 5 and CSS3 skills & Bootstrap 3
- · Computer Networking.
- Software/Hardware installation and configuration.
- C programming.
- Databases
 - · MSSQL Server.
 - MvSOL Server.
 - MongoDB -Beginner
- Mobile
 - Cordova -(angular-mobile)/js

EXPERIENCE

FLEX COMMUNICATIONS LIMITED

Software Developer | Nairobi, Nairobi | April 2016 - Present Software Developer with google maps for tracking and In-house Development

COMPULYNX LIMITED

IT Support Engineer | Nairobi, Nairobi | August 2014 - April 2016 Software Support Engineer and SQL database

SELF-EMPLOYED

PHP and Web Developer | Nairobi, Ny | January 2012 - Present Handle personal client for web development applications

JAMBO PAY EXPRESS

Software developer | Nairobi, Nairobi | February 2014 - August 2014 Revenue Collection Systems development

KISII COUNTY

Technical Support Kisii University | Kisii, Kisii | May 2013 - November 2013 IT Support Engineer -internship in the ICT section

COCA COLA COMPANY LIMITED

ITIntern | Kisii, Kisii | June 2012 - August 2012 IT Intern in ICT department

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE Computer Science

Egerton University

1 2013

2009-2013 Egerton University, Bachelor of Science, Computer Science(second class-upper).

CERTIFICATE (KCSE) A minus -78 points

Cardinal Otunga High School

1 2007

2004-2007 Cardinal Otunga High School, Mosocho. Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE) A minus.

CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION KCPE

1 2003

1996-2003 Kenya Certificate of Primary Education(KCPE)

3/21/2017 ResumeHelp

CERTIFICATIONS

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE) Kenya Certificate of Primary Education(KCPE)

LANGUAGES

Kiswahili -Fluent English Fluent Ekegusii Native

INTERESTS

- Playing and watching football.
- · Watching documentaries.
- Coding.
- · Googling new stuff

PROJECTS

Kisii Revenue Collection System High Management System Vehicle Tracking System(With Ticketing) API Development

REFERENCES

Wilfred Gikaru,

Chairman of department (computer science), 0723620899, wgikaru@gmail.com

Edna Ongalo,

Human Resource Manager Compulynx Limited, 0722912258, hr@compulynx.org, 79013-00400

Lawi Mbira,

CEO Jambo Pay Express,

0720119813, lmbira@umojapay.com

AWARDS

Best Student Cardinal Otunga High School 2007